collective-media.com 2014-06-26

# Collective | Privacy Policy

### JANUARY 24, 2014

The protection of individual privacy is critically important to us. Collective’s combination of proprietary and partner technology allows us to deliver relevant, targeted content to individuals, but not at the expense of individual privacy.

This Privacy Policy describes how we gather information from you when you visit the web sites of Collective, including Ensemble by Collective, and when we serve advertisements on our network of web sites, why we collect this information, and how we may use and share this information.

###### DATA COLLECTION

Collective may collect Data from your computer or device when you are visiting a Collective web site or on a third party’s behalf when we serve advertisements on our network of web sites. This Data may include information such as your IP address, web pages which have been viewed by you, date and time, domain type, and your responses to an advertisement delivered by us or a third party advertising technology vendor. This is information which does not immediately reveal your identity. Nor will we use this information to attempt to discern your identity.

We may use different types of technologies, such as cookies, pixels, and other technologies to collect this Data. We do not collect the following information that identifies you: your name, address, email address, and telephone number (“Personally Identifiable Information” or “PII”) unless you choose to provide it to us. We do not combine the data we collect with this PII. You may elect not to allow us to use Data for delivering targeted advertising by following the Choice procedures set forth below.

We do not ask for PII other than as outlined below for business purposes. We don’t collect PII via our corporate Web site, www.collective.com unless you choose to provide it to us – for example, by sending us your PII in an email. Some of the Collective partner websites may ask people to register and provide PII. None of this PII is combined by Collective with other Data and/or used by Collective for our ad serving.

###### **NON-SENSITIVE HEALTH DATA**

Where permitted by applicable laws governing online privacy, Collective uses non-sensitive health-related data segments to serve or optimize advertisements. In order to provide transparency around these data segments, we have provided a list below: ** _  
_**

Psychographic : Interest : Health  
---  
Search : Health : Beauty : Hair Care  
Search : Business & Finance : Insurance : Health Insurance  
Search : Health : Beauty  
Inmarket : CPG : Health  
Inmarket : CPG : Health : Nutrition  
Inmarket : Services : Health : Medical Centers  
Psychographic : Interest : Health  
Psychographic : Interest : Health : Healthy Living  
Psychographic : Interest : Charity : Health  
Purchase : Retail : Health & Beauty : Hair Care  
Psychographic: Interest : Career Seekers : Health Care  
Inmarket : Financial : Insurance : Health Care Insurance  
Inmarket : CPG : Beauty : Health & Beauty  
Inmarket : CPG : Beauty : Health & Beauty : Beauty and Health Products  
Inmarket : CPG : Beauty : Health & Beauty : Hair Care  
Inmarket : CPG : Beauty : Health & Beauty : Skin Care  
Inmarket : CPG : Beauty : Health & Beauty : Nail Care  
Inmarket : CPG : Beauty : Health & Beauty : Luxury Beauty Products  
Inmarket : CPG : Beauty : Health & Beauty : Teeth Whitening  
Inmarket : CPG : Health : Contact Lenses  
Inmarket : CPG : Health : Eyeglasses  
Inmarket : CPG : Health : Health Aids  
Inmarket : CPG : Health : Over the Counter Drugs  
Inmarket : CPG : Health : Vitamins  
Inmarket : CPG : Health : Cold & Flu Remedies  
Inmarket : CPG : Health : Prescription Medication  
Inmarket : CPG : Health : Children’s Healthcare  
Inmarket : CPG : Health : Elder Care  
Inmarket : CPG : Health : Herbal Remedies  
Search : Business & Finance : Insurance : Health Insurance  
Psychographic : Interest : Health : Medicare Coverage  
Psychographic : Interest : Health : Nutrition  
Psychographic : Interest : Health : Weight Control  
Psychographic : Interest : Health : Supplements  
Purchase : Mail Order : Health & Beauty  
Purchaser : Nutrition, Health & Beauty : Diet & Fitness  
Lifestyle : Affinity (Interests & Daily Activities) : Health  
Purchaser : Nutrition, Health & Beauty : Health & Beauty  
Inmarket : CPG : Health : Drug Store  
Inmarket : Financial : Insurance : Health  
Inmarket : Services : Health Club  
Psychgraphic : Past Purchase History : Financial : Insurance : Health  
Psychographic : Past Purchase History : Retail : Health & Beauty  
Psychographic : Past Purchase History : Retail : Health & Beauty : Drug Store  
Financial : Financial Services : Insurance Customers : Health  
Psychographic : Interest : Fitness  
Psychographic : Interest : Health : Dieting  
Lifestyle : Affinity (Interests & Daily Activities) : Charitable Donor : Health  
Purchase : CPG : Health : Personal Care  
Purchaser : Nutrition, Health & Beauty : Weight Loss & Supplements  
Purchaser : Nutrition, Health & Beauty : Cosmetics Buyers  
Purchaser : Nutrition, Health & Beauty : Energy Drink Buyers  
Purchaser : Nutrition, Health & Beauty : Natural & Organic  
Purchaser : Nutrition, Health & Beauty : Sports Drink Buyers  
Purchaser : Nutrition, Health & Beauty : Value Haircare  
Purchaser : Nutrition, Health & Beauty : Vitamin Buyers  
Purchase : CPG : Health : Allergy Sufferers  
Purchase : CPG : Health : Analgesics  
Inmarket : CPG : Health : Cold & Flu products  
Inmarket : CPG : Health : Weight Loss products  
Purchaser : Nutrition, Health & Beauty : Weight Loss & Supplements  
Purchaser : Nutrition, Health & Beauty : Food : Gourmet Food  
Purchaser : Nutrition, Health & Beauty : Beauty & Fragrance  
Purchaser : Nutrition, Health & Beauty : Natural Wellness  
Purchaser : Nutrition, Health & Beauty : Healthy & Fit  
Purchaser : Nutrition, Health & Beauty : Natural & Organic  
Purchaser : Nutrition, Health & Beauty : Wellness Buyers  
Purchaser : Nutrition, Health & Beauty : Fitness Buyers  
Financial : Financial Services : Healthcare  
Purchase : Financial Services : Healthcare  
Purchase : CPG : Health  
Psychographic : Interest : Health : Natural  
Psychographic : Interest : Charity : Health  
Psychographic : Interest : Fitness : Healthy Living  
Purchase : Retail : Health & Beauty : Female Merchandise  
Purchase : Retail : Health & Beauty : Self Improvement Products  
Purchase : Retail : Health & Beauty : Male Merchandise  
Purchase : Retail : Health & Beauty : Diet & Weight Loss  
Purchase : Retail : Health & Beauty  
Psychographic : Interest : Entertainment : Magazine Reading : Health  
  
###### **HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION**

Collective may use your Data to better target advertisements and other content to individuals in an effort to create a more relevant experience for each person.

The Data is also used for operation and system management purposes including compliance, public purpose and consumer safety, authentication, verification, fraud prevention and security, billing or product or service fulfillment, or ad reporting or delivery, and market research or product development and as otherwise permitted under the NAI and DAA Principles (see below).

This information may also be combined with data from other sources, and shared with our affiliates and partners for similar use.

###### **INFORMATION REQUESTS**

Any PII you provide may be used by Collective to contact you about services or information requested by you and may be shared between our offices in the United States and the United Kingdom for this purpose. We may share this information with third parties who provide administrative services on our behalf (and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information), as well as pursuant to a court order or to law enforcement or government officials, or otherwise to protect the legal rights or legitimate interests of Collective, its affiliates, partners, and each of their respective investors, directors, officers, employees, agents and suppliers.

From time to time, Collective may conduct surveys through various online methods. When participating in a survey, we may ask you to provide PII. The PII you submit in a survey may be used by Collective for research and measurement purposes,  including to measure the effectiveness of content, advertising or programs.  If you wish to contact use about surveys conducted by Collective, you can reach us by email at [surveys@collective.com](mailto:surveys@collective.com).

###### **COOKIES**

A cookie is a piece of data stored on a user’s hard drive containing information about the user. We use cookies, for example, to provide information to advertisers on users’ web browsing activity. We believe this enables us and our advertiser clients to provide users with a more meaningful web experience.

###### **CHOICE**

Collective is a member of the Network Advertising Initiative and the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”), and adhere to their respective self-regulatory codes. The NAI and DAA administer programs that provide consumer awareness and choices regarding web viewing data. As a member of these programs, we provide choice via the DAA choice tool.

Therefore, if you’d like to exercise that choice with respect to Collective or Ensemble by Collective collecting data from your browser or device in connection with tailoring ads on our network of web sites, [please click here www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices "www.aboutads.info/choices"). When you exercise choice, Collective and/or Ensemble by Collective will place an opt-out cookie on your computer. The opt-out cookie tells us not to collect data from your browser or device to tailor online advertisement campaigns.

###### **DISABLING COOKIES**

If you would prefer not to accept cookies generally, you can:

  * change your browser settings to notify you when you receive a cookie, which lets you choose whether or not to accept it; or
  * set your browser to automatically not accept any cookies.

Please note, however, that cookies are used for a variety of reasons, not just targeting advertising, so this may adversely impact your online experience.

###### **BUSINESS SALE**

As we develop our business, we might sell or buy businesses or assets. In the event of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution or similar event, we reserve the right to include any information we have among the assets transferred to the acquiring company.

###### **CHILDREN**

Collective does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13 through Collective.com, nor via any of our network of websites. If you are under 13, please do not give us any personal information. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s Internet usage and to instruct their children to never provide personal information on any website without parental permission. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided personal information to Collective, please contact us, and we will endeavor to delete that information from our database. Collective complies with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act.

###### **LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES**

This Privacy Policy may contain links to third-party sites, which are maintained by third parties. Please be aware that we are not responsible for and cannot control the privacy policies of these other linked sites or their practices. We suggest that you visit those sites directly for information on their privacy, security, data collection and distribution policies because they may differ from Collective’s own position under this Privacy Policy.

###### **SECURITY**

We have reasonable security measures in place intended to help protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of any Data collected. This includes, but is not limited to the use of firewalls and encryption. However, we are unable to guarantee that the security measures we take will not be penetrated or compromised or that your information will remain secure under all circumstances.

We retain Data used for advertising purpose for up to two years from the last interaction between our cookie and your browser or device.

###### **CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

This Privacy Policy is effective as of the date listed at the top of this policy. We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time, and will post prior notice of any such changes on our web site.

###### **HOW TO CONTACT US**

If you wish to contact us about this Privacy Policy, you can reach us by email at contactus@collective.com or by telephone at 646.722.8550.

###### Collective Headquarters

###### 99 Park Avenue, 5th Floor

###### New York, NY 10016
